<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-22T23:38:51-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html"></title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/22/2020-01-01-designing-against-disagreement-at-the-start-of-the-decade.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="" /><published>2022-03-22T23:38:51-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T23:38:51-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/03/22/2020-01-01-designing-against-disagreement-at-the-start-of-the-decade</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/03/22/2020-01-01-designing-against-disagreement-at-the-start-of-the-decade.html"><![CDATA[<p>A system that everyone needs to rely on for consistency does not itself need to be consistent. That would be nice, but it’s not required. The best example of this is our system of timekeeping, which features all manner of gotchas and exceptions and rules that keep programmers up at night if we can’t use a library that handles them automagically. People love to nitpick and debate over tiny technicalities—the smaller the stakes, the more dogged the fighting—and there is no tinier technicality in timekeeping than when the decades start.</p>

<p>This will be familiar. Whether you’re at a kick-ass New Year’s Eve party or existing on twitter in December during a year ending in 9 or 0, somebody is going to chime in that the decade isn’t actually starting when you think. They’ll say they don’t understand <em>why in the world</em> everyone is so excited about 02020. It’s a willful display of ignorance, as they’re trying to demonstrate their superiority because they truly <em>understand</em> the system. According to them, the decades don’t start on years ending in 0 as in 02020–02029; no, no, no: the decades start from years ending in 1 as in 02021–02030. The best version of this chicanery was people insisting Y2K wouldn’t actually happen until 02001, a full year after the flaw was solved.</p>

<p>What, exactly, does the extra labor required to do an start-of-decade calculation accomplish? Nothing. Where, exactly, does fighting over the start of the decade (for two years out of each of them) get us? Nowhere. The only fringe benefits this view offers devotees is the ability to annoy everybody else and the occasional possibility of stumbling upon a sucker who will judge them smarter for bringing up their technicality. The decades “start at 1” to some because they want to argue that the decades start at 1. Reflexive arguing about minutia is not beneficial to our project of living together and should be considered harmful.</p>

<p>When confronting others with this gotcha, the first question they want to be asked is why this counter-intuitive understanding is happening. <em>That’s a trap</em> to allow them to explain their reasoning, something I’ll get to soon enough.</p>

<p>The first thing we should ask is how this new understanding affects the system; that is, how does starting the decades in years ending in 1 make the system more intuitive in the long run? Demonstrably, it doesn’t. The effect of starting decades at 1 is that we have an argument over when the decades start every decade. More than that, it adds an additional layer of complexity to everything we read about decades as timekeepers: “When this says ‘the 01970s’, is it including 01970 or 01980?” Not to mention that the same issue extends to centuries and millennia. It’s an extremely inefficient outcome, one that will be invisible to people obsessed with arcane technicalities. They’re too accustomed to using arcane technicalities as coins of status to consider if the technicality is actually useful or even the most coherent understanding.</p>

<p>Why do people insist that the decades start at 1? Well, actually, it’s because the decades have 10 years and there was no Year Zero and—<em>Wrong.</em> There was no Year Zero, true enough. However, think about the actual claim beyond this one revealed fact for even one second to expose the hidden lie.</p>

<p>The claim is that the decade having 10 discrete years should be prioritized over the utility of referring to decades by their tens-place digit in the vernacular. Adding a Year Zero would not address this because the First Decade BC and First Decade AD would <em>share a year</em>. That is a completely nonsensical response to an epoch, by definition a separation between two points in time. To make the system truly consistent in the way they want, we would need a third option: two Year Zeros, one for BC and another for AD. That may have been feasible to implement 2000 years ago, but it would not be feasible now. It’s a change of such drastically little value that we do not, in fact, argue for it during these pissing contests. We fight over something equally infeasible and even less beneficial. Also, two Year Zeroes would just look weird, if we’re honest.</p>

<p>We’ve identified the issue, discarded the proposed solution as incorrect, discarded the clean solution as infeasible, and we’re going to resolve for the purposes of this article that this still needs to be “solved.” This isn’t an article offering miracles. There is no perfect solution to this problem-with-no-solution-needed. However, when forced to make a system decision with no clean option, it can help to figure out who will bear the burden of dealing with the technicality you’re about to inject. The proposed solution (starting the decade at 1) asserts that it is OK for 6 billion people to collectively bear that burden from now until the end of time, fighting all along. My proposed solution is to treat the two First Decades as special cases. Yes, the two First Decades had 9 years (00001–00009). Indeed, the two First Centuries had 99 years (00001-00099). It’s really just a fact; you can verify it by visually counting up the dates. What’s more, it’s unlikely First Decade and First Century researchers are even going to blink at this because the number of years in that century is irrelevant to their work. For the rest of us, a special case 2000 years ago is similarly irrelevant and can be thoughtlessly absorbed just like the off-by-one convention of referring to the years 02000-02099 as the “Twenty-First Century.” When you frame it like that, it’s pretty clear that the real solution is to just ignore it rather than bringing it up every 10 years.</p>

<p>The various trade-offs and balances made on paper before a system has actually done anything useful, its upfront design, is only one aspect of that system. Also important is how we continue to extend the system while it develops while in use. The year in which the decade begins could not have been fought over until someone decided that when decades begin was important. Things did not always change rapidly enough for that to be obvious. That cultural reference emerged during the rapidly-changing 20th Century, so the argument over when the decades begin was itself designed and implemented in earnest within the last century, after hundreds of years of uncaring peace. There is no reason to accept this new extension into our timekeeping when it only exists to start fights. Contrast this with the fact that we skip a leap year on years divisible by 100, a gotcha which serves the practical purpose of keeping our years aligned with the seasons. The technicality that there are only 24 leap years in a century rather than the 25 we might expect almost never comes up and we do not fight about it.</p>

<p>Incidentally, you might have noticed the extra zeroes I put in front of the years in this article. That is a practice of the <a href="http://longnow.org/">Long Now Foundation</a>. They decided that it’s important for humanity to think about the progress of time in terms of 10,000 years (the “Long Now”) rather than the short-term squabbles of individual human lifetimes. They promote that idea by zero-extending the year to 5 digits as a reminder that, one day, we will reach the Year 10000. This is a marvelous example of extending a system for a purpose while maintaining the intuitive meaning, and its ease of use should be a guiding example for the rest of us.</p>

<p>The common case should be easy; if a person can determine the decade just by looking at the date with no math, that is about as easy as it could ever get. If your extension to the system makes the common case hard or unclear, it’s a bad extension. Moreover, our design process should be hostile to common disagreements, eliminating and refusing to adopt them at every turn. There’s no reason to add a semantic difference of opinion where one did not previously exist. If your extension to the system causes a common disagreement, it’s a bad extension. Yet we have accepted such a difference of opinion into our timekeeping and it is designed to make us disagree until the end of time. When in doubt, where the shift in understanding makes very little to no difference, just allow the intuitive understanding to be correct. (Just because I can hear the TERFs calling: trans people are not a difference of opinion. They are a fact. Designs that ignore them have never reflected reality, and the practical purpose of those designs has always been to marginalize people who are different.)</p>

<p>If we think there’s somebody on our shoulders forcing our hand, that’s just our work with computers biasing our minds. The way the computer prioritizes consistency over sense doesn’t need to dictate how we organize the world. Nobody is forcing your decades to have 10 years stretching from here to eternity. Nobody is forcing you to be a contrarian and fight over minutiae, even if you’re “right” and especially when you’re wrong. Nobody is forcing you to design systems that allow these fights to go on indefinitely. Nobody is forcing you to build arguments into systems that are puttering along just fine.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/03/22/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2022-03-22T23:21:13-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-22T23:21:13-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/03/22/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jekyll/update/2022/03/22/welcome-to-jekyll.html"><![CDATA[<p>You’ll find this post in your <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">_posts</code> directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">jekyll serve</code>, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</p>

<p>Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP</code></p>

<p>Where <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">YEAR</code> is a four-digit number, <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MONTH</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">DAY</code> are both two-digit numbers, and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">MARKUP</code> is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.</p>

<p>Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:</p>

<figure class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-ruby" data-lang="ruby"><span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="p">)</span>
  <span class="nb">puts</span> <span class="s2">"Hi, </span><span class="si">#{</span><span class="nb">name</span><span class="si">}</span><span class="s2">"</span>
<span class="k">end</span>
<span class="n">print_hi</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s1">'Tom'</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="c1">#=&gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.</span></code></pre></figure>

<p>Check out the <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home">Jekyll docs</a> for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll’s GitHub repo</a>. If you have questions, you can ask them on <a href="https://talk.jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll Talk</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Filibuster in the United States Senate</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/20/the-filibuster-in-the-united-states-senate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Filibuster in the United States Senate" /><published>2021-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/03/20/the-filibuster-in-the-united-states-senate</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/03/20/the-filibuster-in-the-united-states-senate.html"><![CDATA[<p>“There’s nothing like having a good quart of scotch with you when you’re falling into the Sun,” said Manchin. “Won’t you join me, gentlemen?”</p>

<p>“Listen to him,” sputtered Warnock. “He’s enjoying this. He likes being cooked in a cubby-holed space ship; he likes to sit here day after day while the floor beneath him is burning his shoes.”</p>

<p>Manchin, the wiry West-Virginian biologist, lowered the half-empty bottle from his lips and scowled at the ship’s doctor. “But not for long, my dear Warnock, not for long. Our fate lies within a few hours. The ship will be drawn closer and closer to the Sun. The heat will become unbearable. Then—pffffft!—the ship will be a little spark—”</p>

<p>“You’re a pain,” growled Captain Harris.</p>

<p>Manchin raised his eyebrows quizzically and grinned. He said nothing, walked to a bunk, and sat down beside Joe, the pilot.</p>

<p>The silence continued for some time, broken only by the footfalls of Captain Harris in her nervous pacing. There was nothing to do but wait. The four of them knew that. The ship couldn’t hold out much longer; it would burst under the terrific strain, would be reduced instantly to a cinder by the Sun’s blistering heat.</p>

<p>They were trapped, falling into the Sun inevitably.</p>

<p>“One meteorite,” said Manchin casually, “one hurtling fragment of some interstellar gadabout which chose to cross our path at the wrong time. That’s all it took to smash our jets and send the four of us toward that fiery mass.”</p>

<p>“Shut up!” snapped Harris. “It’s bad enough without your moaning!”</p>

<p>Oblivious to the captain’s words, Manchin patted his bottle affectionately.</p>

<p>“In the name of Heaven!” growled Warnock, leaping to his feet. “Why do we sit here like a lot of mummies? There’s a rocket capsule aboard, you say, with sufficient power to carry one of us to Mercury. Why don’t we use it? I ask you, Harris.”</p>

<p>“You answered that yourself,” the captain said bluntly. “True, that rocket capsule can carry one of us to Mercury. Just one, understand—there’s room for but one person in a capsule. I ask you—which one of us would that be?”</p>

<p>“That’s beside the point,” muttered Warnock, as he wiped beads of perspiration from his forehead. “You don’t seem to realize what valuable information we possess. Think of that cylinder in the supply room. It contains all the photographs we took of Mercurian plant and animal life, and the photos of Vulcan. To say nothing of the data concerning the Sun’s corona—why, our analysis would be of infinite value to Earth scientists!”</p>

<p>“Quite so,” Harris said crisply. “But while you’re thinking about that, don’t forget the three who would be left aboard this ship—think of what would happen to them.” She stopped her pacing and shook a finger under the doctor’s imposing Van Dyke. “Do you know what would happen to them, Warnock? They’d burn alive—they’d cook—while on Earth your scientists would hop around in glee over a few photographs of Mercury!”</p>

<p>Warnock sat down heavily, exhausted.</p>

<p>“The doc’s right, Harris,” Joe interposed. “There’s no reason for all four of us dying when it’s possible for one to gain freedom. And for God’s sake if you’re going to do something do it in a hurry! We’ll burn before you make up your mind!”</p>

<p>“My mind’s made up,” Harris retorted. “I’m staying. In case you’ve forgotten, a captain is the last one to leave her ship. As for you three, fight it out among yourselves. Draw straws—anything. The consequences will be your worry.”</p>

<p>“I’ll stay,” murmured Manchin, lifting his bottle to his lips.</p>

<p>“You don’t mean that,” said the youthful Joe. “You want to go—we all want to go—but it can only be one of us.”</p>

<p>He fell silent, placing his head in his hands. Harris resumed her pacing.</p>

<p>The ship drifted on, slowly it seemed, ever nearing the solar furnace, falling toward the flames that were eager to dissolve the tiny cruiser locked in an unyielding gravitational pull.</p>

<p>“Soon,” mused Manchin. “Soon we’ll be too close for the rocket capsule to break free of the Sun’s drag. Then there will be no doubt as to what will be done. Ha!”</p>

<p>“Malarkey!” yelled Joe, jerking erect. “How can you be so confounded happy about it all? We’re falling into the Sun, man—doesn’t that have any effect upon you?”</p>

<p>Manchin shrugged. “Perhaps. We are falling into the Sun, yes. We’ll die, no doubt, so my future is definite. I know what is coming. Soon I shall be but a tiny spark, drifting nowhere in a big Sun. Do I regret being a tiny spark? Not when I have my scotch with me.”</p>

<p>“You’re a smart guy,” Joe thrust at him. “Maybe you can tell us how to choose the rocket capsule’s passenger.”</p>

<p>“Simple, my friend. The captain won’t go—she must stay with the ship. I have no relatives, only my scotch, so I am satisfied. The doctor must stay—he’s too fat to get in the capsule. M’sieu Joe, the honor is yours. Au revoir.”</p>

<p>“Don’t be crazy—”</p>

<p>“Do not worry about us, my friend. We will find something to do. Perhaps I can interest the doctor and the captain in three-handed bridge. If not, we’ll wait. We’ll go soon—sssss! Like that.”</p>

<p>Joe buried his face in his hands again.</p>

<p>For a few moments there was an unbroken silence. From the double-insulated hulls emanated a dry hotness that scorched the already blistered air. The hotness increased, rising to a fierce, intolerable degree. It grew, inexorably, pressing against their lungs—</p>

<p>Joe floundered crazily, leaped across the control room and plucked a gun from his locker. “This’ll make it easier,” he gasped, lifting the weapon to his head. “Somebody’s got to fly that capsule—”</p>

<hr />

<p>For ten minutes, no one spoke. It was hard to speak—each breath was a torture to the lungs.</p>

<p>“Manchin,” said Warnock finally, in short gasps, “in God’s name will you get into the capsule and take that cylinder to Mercury? One of us has got to go—for Joe’s sake!”</p>

<p>Manchin, sprawled out on the pilot’s bunk, made no reply. The captain stood before the dull gray view-screen, watched him a moment, thoughtfully. “Can’t you reverse the field?” he asked at length. “I’d like to see the System just once more.”</p>

<p>Harris had already made a few deft motions on the instrument panel. Presently, the screen came to life. Its scope possessed a bright halo—the Sun’s glow. In the center of the screen Mercury was visible, a faint, receding globe. Harris moved the scope slowly until she found the feeble point of light that designated the Earth. She watched it grimly. “Satisfied, Warnock?”</p>

<p>“Dr. Warnock is dead,” came Manchin’s monotone.</p>

<p>Harris turned. The doctor lay on his face, immobile and silent.</p>

<p>“The heat,” said Rogers, “and his age.”</p>

<p>They carried him to the supply room, laid him beside the inert form of Joe.</p>

<p>The two stood watching Earth’s dull glimmer on the screen. The heat pressed them relentlessly, always increasing—</p>

<p>“Take the capsule, Manchin. You’ve no reason to remain.”</p>

<p>“I prefer to stay, Captain Harris. You have relatives—it is only proper that you should fly the capsule.”</p>

<p>“Under any circumstances, Manchin, the captain does not leave her ship in distress. Should I return to Earth without the rest of you, I would lose my rank unquestionably. Now, before we draw too close, take the cylinder to Mercury! You’re a fool not to!”</p>

<p>“M’sieu Harris, I possess magnificent renown as a fool. I shall remain.”</p>

<p>“But the cylinder—”</p>

<p>“The cylinder, Captain Harris, be damned.”</p>

<p>They looked at each other a long minute. Harris, stripped to the waist, perspiring, her thick black hair hanging in her eyes; Manchin, small, wiry, faint traces of a smile lurking on his lips.</p>

<p>Suddenly the floor shook beneath them. A violent shudder passed through the ship from stem to stern. The momentum of the Sunward fall increased.</p>

<p>Regaining her balance, Harris gasped, “Good God—the capsule!”</p>

<p>They saw a flash of light on the screen, saw the tiny rocket streak for Mercury in a flare of brilliance. It dwindled rapidly to a receding speck that was swallowed in the depths of space.</p>

<p>Speechless, Harris and Manchin raced to the supply room. They found Joe there, but no Warnock and no cylinder. Needles on the face of the capsule compartment jutting out from the wall registered zero.</p>

<p>“He was faking,” said Harris. “He wasn’t dead—he merely pretended, the coward!”</p>

<p>Manchin took a quick drink, threw a sidelong glance at Joe’s bloody form, and walked slowly back to the control room. Harris followed. The clicking of their heels made a sullen echo upon the blistered walls.</p>

<p>On the screen, something dim and remote was moving, growing in size. Harris hastened forward in amazement.</p>

<p>“It’s Warnock!” he breathed. “Lord—he was too late—he’s falling back!”</p>

<p>“A pity,” said Manchin. “He has so much longer to wait now. It must be horrible.”</p>

<p>“And the cylinder,” Harris sighed. “All that information will be lost.” Her tired, bloodshot eyes followed the little capsule’s course across the screen, back toward the flaming Sun.</p>

<p>“Perhaps,” remarked Manchin, “there will be another expedition to Mercury some day, another group of scientists, with a better ship and better equipment. And no meteorite will prevent their safe return to Earth.” He hesitated, took two tumblers from a nearby cabinet and filled them with the remaining contents of his bottle. He handed one of them to Harris, took the other himself. “A final toast, Captain?”</p>

<p>Harris accepted. “To the next Mercurian expedition, Manchin.”</p>

<p>“The next expedition, Captain Harris.”</p>

<p>They drank, and Manchin sucked in a breath. “I say—it’s getting a bit warm in here, isn’t it?”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="fiction," /><category term="politics," /><category term="shortstory," /><category term="plagiarism" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our slow descent into the red-hot gravity well.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google’s Certificate Training Program is About Power</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/google-s-certificate-training-program-is-about-power.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google’s Certificate Training Program is About Power" /><published>2020-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/google-s-certificate-training-program-is-about-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/21/google-s-certificate-training-program-is-about-power.html"><![CDATA[<p><em>When I write things, I must strike when the iron is hot or the fire leaves me and I have another incomplete project. This has turned into one of them. Unlike the others, I find I don’t hold out hope that the fire will come back here. The idea has a Best By date that’s probably already passed and, as with some other pieces, the idea (at first tantalizing) has become so obvious to me that I find the dance required to turn it into a cogent essay intolerable. I stand by the points raised within enough that I’ll put it out there anyway. Nonetheless, it is ultimately incomplete and I don’t want to finish it. In a better world, I would have figured out the way to merge the narratives together into one line instead of leaving the claims separate. I just didn’t and won’t.</em></p>

<hr />

<p>On August 4, Google announced its <a href="https://grow.google/certificates/">Career Certificates Program</a>, a partnership with Coursera that offers training in basic technical topics as a launchpad into tech careers. It’s a MOOC bootcamp or microdegree, basically, and the initial offering is for “IT support specialists.” Courses for data analysts, project managers, and UX designers will be the second wave, and the program will doubtless expand if it’s popular. The thing that separated this from any other private partnership between an industry titan and Coursera was Google’s promise to treat the degrees the same as four-year university degrees for the purpose of hiring.</p>

<p>Immediately after this, more than one White Guy In Tech decided to show his entire ass by recycling his complaints about bootcamps generally. Essentially, they said the six-month program could not possibly prepare people to work in tech because it couldn’t provide all the things four-year degrees promises. This is, obviously, credentialist gatekeeping. This is, obviously, erasing the experiences of people who self-studied their way into tech. It’s even specious on its own terms just because it assumes four-year degrees live up to their lofty promises just by existing. However, discussing these complaints further would be a huge waste of time. In rushing to throw people with different educational backgrounds under the bus, they missed a huge and obvious truth: there is no universe where Google being in charge of a “degree-equivalent” program is OK.</p>

<p>Let’s start with the problem Career Certificate Program aims to solve. Ostensibly, it is meant to ease entry into the tech industry for newbie outsiders. This is inherently rooted in the premise that there is a shortage of technical talent that can’t fill all the jobs companies want to create, which is a lie. Companies like Google have been investing heavily in that lie for at least as long as I can remember. There are more than enough people who trained in the “traditional” path, who did everything “right,” who don’t end up getting hired no matter how much they try. A lot of them are people of color. As much as I could center racism on this topic all day long, and will return to it within this very post, the most obvious way that this lie does not comport with reality is that most software jobs go to people with connections at the company. The entire job search process sans-connections is a treadmill designed to wear people down until they’ll accept anything or give up. Rather than solve the actual problems of fitting people who are already trained into roles that already sit vacant, companies like Google and Microsoft are all about training “new generations” of technologists.</p>

<p>There are a lot of potential reasons for that. Because these companies insist on hiding behind PR and employee silence, we can only speculate, hence the entirety of this article. One possibility is that Google intends to glut the labor market with suckers who’ll accept lower pay as the supply of labor increases, but I’m not interested in turning to such matters. I’d rather stick to ideas about how the power dynamic shifts. What power does Google hope to gain by creating a pathway into the industry that it controls?</p>

<hr />

<p>This is not a promise of better education or a promise of improving the industry. This is, first-and-foremost a PR move and a power play.</p>

<p>This is a play for controlling what software developers learn. A year after launch, people will complain about companies not accepting Google microdegrees, similar to the bootcamp stigma. But, here, it will be a corpus trained on Google tech, clamoring to work using Google tech.</p>

<p>Just one bad thing about Google setting up a bootcamp is that Google would have direct control over its employment pipeline and its engineers’ basic education. That’s super not their place. Those things should be socially mediated.</p>

<p>Another bad thing about the Google microdegree is that it will provide another layer of Google-controlled deniability in its hiring. The demographics of who gets to take it will be important. The demographics of who actually gets hired through it will be doubly important.</p>

<p>Google charging any amount of money for this program is laughable. It’s a billion-dollar megacorporation. It could eat the costs of this program without thinking about it, just like its massive slush fund for failed projects eats all the stillborn projects that never see the light of day.</p>

<hr />

<p>The “degree-equivalent” bit is branding. To be fair, the entire university degree system is about branding. But to be balanced, the purpose of Google branding the certificates this way is to turn them into an industry virus. When the students mysteriously do not get hired by Google, will they take their $300 degrees with them to colleges around the country? No, they’ll be at least minimally ready for work (and all the credentialists know it), so they will take their degree-equivalent certificates to other companies and ask for jobs. This means Google would have a corpus of dedicated learners going forth, representing themselves as trained on Google products. All a company would have to do to tap into that excess would be to adopt Google products. Which is super not-trivial, but it would still be a pressure. Outside of Google, I’d be surprised if it took a year for the articles to start coming out about how other companies should be treating the Career Certificate Program as an undergraduate degree. It’s just an appealing underdog narrative in general.</p>

<p>Not everybody who takes this degree will be hired by Google. This degree-replacement is not a commitment to hire people from the program. It may be a way to funnel more people into their hiring system, but the Google hiring process is a discriminatory meat grinder. We shouldn’t assume that more people entering the process means more people hired over time, especially considering that Google already gets thousands and thousands of applicants for every position. Besides, why should we want more people to go through their discriminatory abuse process? If nothing else changes, the disparities caused by their misguided interviewing will just continue. What’s the good in that?</p>

<hr />

<p>They do this training shit and target non-white people in order to sell hope, and then they don’t hire these people. They just don’t. <a href="https://dev.to/lethargilistic/happy-juneteenth-now-hire-some-black-folks-g24">The demographics of these companies’ technical teams has never changed</a>. They train these people up and then send them out into the world with dashed hopes of working for Google, only to face the reality that non-white people are rarities at all the other companies, too. Is that Google’s hope? That these people will be trained up and then other places will just magically start hiring them? My guess is yes. These wannabe Googlers will be trained on Google technologies and if they get hired elsewhere they might want to evangelize for Google technologies once they have the clout to do so.</p>

<p>Understand Google’s hiring practices. They have historically funneled most of the resources of their organization to the enrichment of white people, whatever else they project via PR. Google’s diversity initiatives are not to be trusted even slightly. They are, in effect, a white supremacist organization. They must be treated with the highest level of suspicion. If the team behind it is not anticipating that, and they are not already thinking about the ideas in this article, then they’re not doing their job. But, in all likelihood, they are. In launching the project, they have already abandoned the pro-social path of not trying to leverage their way into developer education. To be fair, they were already doing that through universities. But to be balanced, this is an idea that can only grow in scope and Google shouldn’t even be asking to take responsibly of an in-house alternative education path. It’s a disastrous idea that could turn out very badly for everyone who isn’t connected to Google executives.</p>

<hr />

<p>As a general rule, there are always better ways to criticize an idea from a billion-dollar mega-corporation that regularly fucks people up just because it can than “wow, people really won’t enter the industry like I did, huh?”</p>

<p>Just another day in 2020 hellworld. I’m sure the people working on the Google microdegree are very happy with themselves and the white supremacy organization they work for. We’ll see what happens.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="career," /><category term="culture," /><category term="google," /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It's a Trap.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the last great american plagiarist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/14/the-last-great-american-plagiarist.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the last great american plagiarist" /><published>2020-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/14/the-last-great-american-plagiarist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/14/the-last-great-american-plagiarist.html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20130303045356/http://thegraybook.livejournal.com/">Cassandra</a> rode up to the City of Bones, it was sunny
<a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/amberjamieson/jk-rowling-antitrans-statement">That passé TERF’s little screed</a> sent her mind back to fanfic
Draco, the heir to the Malfoys’ bad name, was funny
And the site said, “How did this cutting-edge first-timer do it?”
The writing was charming, if a little gauche
There’s only so far het <em>Potter</em> goes
<a href="https://fanlore.org/wiki/The_Draco_Trilogy">She picked out a name and called it <em>Dormiens</em></a>…
The fandom was raving, and a little proud
They learned that <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20081209131040/http://www.journalfen.net/community/bad_penny/8985.html">she copied</a> and turned around
It must have been bad that they’d loved her so</p>

<p>And they said
There goes the last great American <a href="https://ssrn.com/abstract=3462144">plagiarist</a>
Who knows, if she never showed up, what could’ve been?
There goes the maddest woman FanFiction’s ever seen
She had a marvelous time ruining everything</p>

<p>Cassandra got banned from FanFiction.net forever
For her love of sharing quotes in her novels
Filled the books with phrases and worked with the big names
And blew through the process with a laugh and some <em>Buffy</em>
And she loved her book and, yeah, <a href="https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/DracoInLeatherPants">so did they</a></p>

<p>And they said
There goes the last great American <a href="https://ssrn.com/abstract=3664444">plagiarist</a>
Who knows, if she never showed up, what could’ve been?
There goes the most shameless woman FanFiction’s ever seen
She had a marvelous time ruining everything</p>

<p>They say <a href="https://www.cassandraclare.com/">she was seen on occasion</a>
Publishing books, scoping out her new trilogies
And the fans got what they wanted
She used the tropes and made sure she was seen
Twenty years is a long time
The <em>Draco</em> Books all survive and they’re still free
<a href="https://dev.to/lethargilistic/copyright-holders-are-landlords-and-it-s-not-ok-289h">Free of Authors with power</a>, their plagiarized glowers,
And it’s all a part of me</p>

<p>Who knows, if I never showed up, what could’ve been?
There goes the loudest person this forum’s ever seen
I had a marvelous time ruining everything!</p>

<p>I had a marvelous time
    ruining everything.
A marvelous time
    Ruining Everything.
A marvelous time!</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/lethargilistic/status/1233487416905826306">I had a marvelous time.</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="poetry," /><category term="plagiarism," /><category term="culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[When a plagiarist makes it, it's all poetry.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Books to Fight Technopoly</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/02/5-books-to-fight-technopoly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Books to Fight Technopoly" /><published>2020-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/08/02/5-books-to-fight-technopoly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/08/02/5-books-to-fight-technopoly.html"><![CDATA[<p>This era is a time of unprecedented technological advance. Every day, someone jumps out of the woodwork with a new gadget that they claim will solve a problem you don’t even know you have. Perhaps it does. However, there’s an implicit demand from all of this technology and automation that usually goes unexamined by the zeitgeist: ignore the unintended consequences. Ignore the intrusion of advertising in public places previously immune to it. Ignore the predatory surveillance. Ignore <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/15/technology/myanmar-facebook-genocide.html">the actual genocide facilitated by our platform</a>.</p>

<p>We’ve been dealing with unintentional consequences of technology since the invention of the alphabet (and it <em>was</em> an invented technology) harmed our ability to remember things. We’ve been able to adapt to such changes over long periods of time and make trade-offs that benefited us, but today’s technologists are not interested in the time it takes for technology to assimilate. As such, their stated good intentions fall flat next to their destructive effects.</p>

<p>We too often default to viewing new technology as good in and of itself, as the Technopolists wish. Then we fail to follow that up with the serious discussion of the effects of that technology that these changes demand. When those downsides become so apparent that we can no longer ignore them, we treat that introduced technology as though it had always existed, making opposition to it unthinkable. If we’re allowed to pursue reforms at all, proposed limitations are curtailed because our culture still thinks of technology as a good end in and of itself. The elimination of actual harms does not seem to be required. And then, if we get minimal protections for people, the limitations are perpetually at risk of being destroyed by government corruption like Net Neutrality was.</p>

<p>I don’t know if it makes the situation better or worse, but at each reckless step, there have been detractors. They do not usually object to the concept of modern technology itself. Rather, they object to the mindset that technology and change are inherently good, and that technology’s indiscriminate advance is strictly good for society. In challenging that orthodoxy, these writers show us inconvenient truths that exploitative technologists are happy to hide. Here is a list of 5 such books that are worth reading.</p>

<h1 id="1-technopoly-1992-by-neil-postman">1) <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technopoly"><em>Technopoly</em></a> (1992) by Neil Postman</h1>
<p><img src="https://thepracticaldev.s3.amazonaws.com/i/glfzt9j3h7vu6c0oio3f.jpg" alt="Technopoly cover" /></p>

<p><em>Technopoly</em> is the most important book about technology of the 20th Century.</p>

<p>The short book is dense with information and frameworks for how to think about abuse of technology. Frequently, we casually allow our tools, whether machine or ideology, to shape culture in ways that benefit the few at the great expense of the many’s very humanity.</p>

<p><em>Technopoly</em> is social criticism about technology, but it is not an anti-technology book; it is an anti-Technopoly book. Technopoly is a collection of radical normative claims about how technology should shape the world that people have increasingly adopted since invention became tied to commercialism and efficiency. It may seem obvious to us that more efficiency is inherently good, as this mindset pervades our culture, but this belies a gross disregard for other people. The Technopolist encourages others to denigrate the past in order to push their new products, disregarding alternative opinions as “Luddite.” It places that efficiency of operation above consideration of the abilities of human beings, leading to the creation of new systems that don’t serve humans well and the increasing estrangement of us from functional older systems in ways that make our lives strictly worse.</p>

<p>This happens because the Technopolist does not care about leveraging technology intelligently to pursue a better world. Instead, they pursue new technology as the end in and of itself, claiming that will be the cure to human suffering because because human suffering is caused by human inefficiencies. This leads to creating things without consideration of any negative consequences that reveal themselves later. Basically, they say “move fast and break things,” because they very wrongly believe that the things that break couldn’t matter. It is morbid misanthropy couched in techno-utopianism.</p>

<p>Further, as much as they phrase these ideals as the cure to society’s ills for PR purposes, the reality is that our most difficult problems are social and cannot adequately be solved by the addition of new technology. Indiscriminate applications of technology can make them exponentially worse. One of the key reasons for this is that, technology does not sit neutrally in our world. The fact that technology can radically change the way that someone approaches one problem at hand is only the most germane possible consequence. A change to technological conditions can also radically change a person’s sense of self. For example, consider how the addition of a vehicle fundamentally changes someone’s sense of how big the world is, or how people in skilled jobs that are increasingly automated begin to view themselves as unskilled monitors. On top of that, it’s important to realize that technology is <em>designed</em>, and we must be vigilant in understanding that the technologists behind it may want to direct that change to benefit themselves above others, such as how Facebook made itself somewhat indispensable by <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2018/4/28/17293056/facebook-deletefacebook-social-network-monopoly">fundamentally changing the way interpersonal networking functioned with its emotional labor machine</a>.</p>

<p><em>Technopoly</em> reminds us that technology exists to serve us; humans do not exist to serve technology. It is important to actually analyze and evaluate the effects of new technologies instead of blindly moving from one to the next and assuming the answer <em>must</em> be a <em>new</em> technology. Furthermore, we must keep our guards up against Technopolists’ encouragement to abandon our cultural memory. Often you’ll find that many new applications of technology that have caused massive social welfare problems in our time are shockingly new.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Every company’s leveraging of the internet to insert itself into your life or curtail your expectations of privacy must have come after the Internet, which only became commercially available about 30 years ago.</li>
  <li>Andrew Wakefield’s fraudulent anti-vaccination paper, which inspired much of the current wave of anti-vaccination insanity, was published in 1998.</li>
  <li>Movie theatres once treated your ticket as the only payment necessary to see the film, and they only began requiring you to watch pre-film commercials in the mid-1990s.</li>
  <li>The Originalist approach to the United States Constitution, used to provide inappropriate second-hand legitimacy to extreme conservative politics in the judiciary, was <a href="https://www.commondreams.org/views/2018/09/04/brett-kavanaugh-and-triumph-conservative-counterrevolution">essentially invented and formalized in the 1970s</a>, boosted by the <a href="http://reclaimdemocracy.org/powell_memo_lewis/">Powell Manifesto</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>These are blips in the cultural consciousness, but their creators want you to believe they are immutable and inextricable features of our world, that have always been this way and always shall be. They did not, and constant reevaluation of their place is essential so that their real consequences may be understood and properly mitigated. Technology, whether tool or toy or ideology, must be treated seriously and critically, not as a sacred cow.</p>

<h1 id="2-geek-heresy-2015-by-kentaro-toyama">2) <a href="https://geekheresy.org/"><em>Geek Heresy</em></a> (2015) by Kentaro Toyama</h1>
<p><img src="https://thepracticaldev.s3.amazonaws.com/i/62rx87aw637so6c94ven.jpg" alt="Geek Heresy cover" />
Also a contender for a list of the worst-titled books, <em>Geek Heresy</em> is not really about being a geek, nor necessarily a heretic. The title is sort-of a preemptive and misguided apology to its target audience, technologists who believe that any social problem can be adequately addressed by installing some targeted software and hardware solution. This is completely untrue, and Toyama’s explanation is a simple aphorism, <em>The Law of Amplification</em>: “Like a lever, technology amplifies people’s capacities in the direction of their intentions.” To demonstrate the implications of this Law, Toyama walks us through his considerable experiences as a technological innovator trying to modernize rural populations in India.</p>

<p>It is extremely common for paternalistic groups to target people with fewer technological resources, donate a number of computers with an educational program, then pat themselves on the back while leaving those people to fend for themselves. Often, they don’t succeed, because of the Law of Amplification: the technology amplifies what the people want to do with it. If someone is intrinsically interested in educating themselves, they are more likely to use a computer to explore new things and do that exponentially more effectively than they would without one. If they are intrinsically interested in entertaining themselves, as most children tend to be, then the addition of computers can be a distraction in class exponentially worse than anything else. As a result, many (most?) of these attempts at indiscriminately throwing technology at problems results in little to no betterment of these peoples’ lives and they reject them entirely. The book is peppered with examples of what happens to the donated computers when they are taken out of classrooms as ineffective. And where are the benefactors while these programs fail? Shopping around the results of earlier, smaller, successful pilots for the failed program to new areas, never looking back.</p>

<p>The Law of Amplification is more general than education. It’s useful for evaluating the purported goals of any technology, and helpful for spotting the unintended consequences that are the core of Toyama’s book. For example, Facebook’s technology <em>amplifies</em> its <em>capacity</em> to surveil and sell advertising in the direction of its <em>intention</em> to reach the world population. <a href="https://www.sup.org/books/title/?id=25991"><em>Adcreep</em> by Mark Bartholemew</a> is a good book to read if you’re curious about the strange, unpleasant, and unprecedented places our unregulated advertising regime is taking us.</p>

<h1 id="3-race-after-technology-2019-by-ruha-benjamin">3) <a href="https://www.ruhabenjamin.com/race-after-technology"><em>Race After Technology</em></a> (2019) by Ruha Benjamin</h1>
<p><img src="https://dev-to-uploads.s3.amazonaws.com/i/vy8wwxlpfgkfc1vkfjdy.jpg" alt="Race After Technology cover" /></p>

<p><em>Race After Technology</em> is essential. It is a point-by-point survey of the ways that our current approach to the development of software creates and enforces artificial differences between groups of people. Our world has been constructed with design decisions that make thriving in everyday life easy for some and impossible for many others. Obviously, the book has its eye turned toward race, but the same is equally true for other groups of people who are not seen as the “default” in a society. The book looks at the issue through the lens of the “New Jim Code”:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The employment of new technologies that reflect and reproduce existing inequities but that are promoted and perceived as more objective or progressive than the discriminating systems of a previous era.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Technology has a certain amount of power to shape the way that we think. The idea of using it to correct the sins of our world is very appealing. However, the sins of our world are social problems and technology is as sensitive to them as it is designed to be. Not only that, once a technological system is in place and automating decisions, it can be a nightmare to replace because our cognition of the system changes when we think of its results as computerized and calculated and correct.</p>

<p>In other words, technology is a tool and the way those tools are implemented matters. Malicious technologies amplify “traditional” inequities in very predictable ways, and reading this book will show you how to spot them in the wild. Even better, reading it will give you insights into the social dynamics behind those technological decisions, because all of those approaches to social problems were designed in a particular social context. For example, the “datafication of injustice” is everywhere, even before it is used to justify encoding biases into machines—think of how “black-on-black crime” statistics are used to justify increased policing of black people when the same is never true of “white-on-white crime.” Well, those same statistical tricks are used to justify algorithms that automate the decision to police black neighborhoods more.</p>

<p>What the New Jim Code represents is a failure to listen to the voices of the people we know are oppressed. People who do not want to engage in that necessary work, who are ignorant of these issues or else revel in their complicity with them, have been systematically put in power for decades. If you are not those people, you have to work under those people, and those people have spent a huge amount of time and money in making analyses of systemic racism seem ridiculous. You owe it to yourself to explicitly correct subtly white supremacist ideas that have permeated your mind.</p>

<h1 id="4-the-glass-cage-2014-by-nicholas-carr">4) <a href="http://www.nicholascarr.com/?page_id=18"><em>The Glass Cage</em></a> (2014) by Nicholas Carr</h1>
<p><img src="https://thepracticaldev.s3.amazonaws.com/i/mu64pj4z5pmu2k77l9yh.jpg" alt="The Glass Cage cover" /></p>

<p>This book is Carr’s exploration of the potential effects of automation in modern life. Of course, most people like automation in the sense that they can pick up their phones and look up information or they love the idea of a world with cars that drive themselves. However, Carr and the many researchers whose work he distills in this book have very credible worries that the insatiable breadth and expansion of modern automation is currently having negative effects. We expand automation to new fields under the banner of alleviating human error and making people not have to work as hard, but it often does the opposite: automating systems that require skill can cause the people to become complacent.</p>

<p>That’s not because these people are lazy or unnecessary, as a technologist might say. It’s because they are human and these systems are being designed in ways that don’t work with humans. They fundamentally change the nature of the work, and indeed the nature of the people who do that work, so they go from craftsmen to glorified monitors. These jobs go from interesting work that a person may become good at and find satisfying to work that is, in many ways, impossible for humans to do. In fact, the problem is often compounded further when these systems are designed to be openly hostile and distrusting of humans. Developers of these hardware and software solutions come to think of these users as idiots whose mistakes must be abstracted away in the nature of efficiency, even though they are designing systems that quantifiably drive people to make more mistakes than non-automated systems.</p>

<h1 id="5-the-design-of-everyday-things-1988-by-donald-norman">5) <a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/design-everyday-things"><em>The Design of Everyday Things</em></a> (1988) by Donald Norman</h1>
<p><img src="https://thepracticaldev.s3.amazonaws.com/i/hcspkwy6nr4zm93gas74.jpg" alt="The Design of Everyday Things cover" /></p>

<p>Most of this post has been doom-and-gloom because of how deeply this Technopoly thinking has permeated modern day culture. As these books show, it has been opposed intellectually, but we don’t see much material resistance to it otherwise. It does exist in the fields of human factors and ergonomics, of which this is an approachable and seminal book.</p>

<p><em>The Design of Everyday Things</em> is about a lot of specific ways that we build things that don’t seem to be made for a world inhabited by humans, for use by humans. The most famous examples used in this book are, of course, the <a href="https://99percentinvisible.org/article/norman-doors-dont-know-whether-push-pull-blame-design/">Norman Doors</a>, tools that we have been creating for hundreds of years and yet still make new models of that require signs and labels to tell us how to open them…because, without those, everyone opens the door incorrectly. They do not match our mental models of the handle and door, and this is <em>not</em> your fault. One of the things that designers get to take advantage of is people’s instinctive and habitual predilection for apologizing to machines. The machines get the benefit of the doubt because we assume we must have been wrong and need to become more skilled. Norman’s radical take on this dynamic was to place the blame where it belongs: with the designer. We don’t open the door incorrectly. The door was designed incorrectly, so that it was at odds with the mental models of the people who would use it.</p>

<p>These examples may often be funny, but they are not necessarily accidents because they are often the product of a profound lack of empathy on the part of the designer.</p>

<p>Also, apparently, Donald Norman also wrote a book called <a href="https://www.jnd.org/books/things-that-make-us-smart-defending-human-attributes-in-the-age-of-the-machine.html"><em>Things That Make Us Smart: Defending Human Attributes In The Age Of The Machine</em></a>, which has a very appealing title. In <a href="https://www.jnd.org/books/living-with-complexity.html"><em>Living with Complexity</em></a>, which I have read, Norman’s explicit demarcation of complexity and confusion as states of the world and mind is extremely useful and Good.</p>

<h1 id="future-reading">Future Reading</h1>
<p>I’m self-conscious about most of this list being written by white men, so here are some books I’m planning to read that aren’t:</p>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674970977"><em>A People’s History of Computing in the United States</em></a> (2018) by Joy Lisi Rankin</li>
  <li><a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/programmed-inequality"><em>Programmed Inequality: How Britain Discarded Women Technologists and Lost Its Edge in Computing</em></a> (2017) by Marie Hicks</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.dukeupress.edu/dark-matters"><em>Dark Matters: On the Surveillance of Blackness</em></a> (2015) by Simone Browne</li>
  <li><a href="https://weaponsofmathdestructionbook.com/"><em>Weapons of Math Destruction: How Big Data Increases Inequality and Threatens Democracy</em></a> (2016) by Cathy O’Neil</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="reading," /><category term="technology," /><category term="books," /><category term="history" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Humans do not exist to serve technology or Technopolists.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Citation of Matters Called Ideas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/26/the-citation-of-matters-called-ideas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Citation of Matters Called Ideas" /><published>2020-07-26T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/26/the-citation-of-matters-called-ideas</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/26/the-citation-of-matters-called-ideas.html"><![CDATA[<p>Citation. What is citation? How does it travel? Why do we see the distant footnote in Marx before we hear its thunder? Why does a paper seem to sound many tomes when it is analyzed? Such questions as these baffled the wisest people for centuries. Today, however, the science of citation is one of the best understood of all the many branches of rent-seeking. The mystery has disappeared.</p>

<p>Every kind of citation has its beginning in an influence we discover. That influence may be a published dissertation or a conversation we overhear or a barking dog. Whatever it is, some part of it vibrates within the mind while we contemplate it. The influence disturbs our inert thoughts in such a way that <em>ideas</em> are produced. These ideas travel out in all directions, expanding in balloon-like fashion from the source of the idea. If the ideas happen to reach our limbs, they set up derivative objects which we observe as influence.</p>

<p>Ideas, then, depend on three things. There must be a vibrating influence to set up the ideas, an artifact created to capture the ideas, and someone’s mind to receive them. Ideas can travel through a vacuum, though that won’t stop people from trying to tax that travel.</p>

<p>There is an old catch question concerning the definition of <em>citation</em>: If a citation falls in an unread margin, does its presence make any idea? The answer, of course, depends on how we define <em>idea</em>. If we think of it as the ink in the margin that may hypothetically be followed up upon by a real reader after it has been indexed by citation metric services, the answer is yes. Wherever there is the potential influence, there are ideas. But if we think of ideas as a sensation of the mind, the answer must be no. The two definitions are equally correct, and scientists insist on the one that makes their metrics go up (sometimes with their bank accounts) and never the one which might change the world.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="philosophy," /><category term="culture," /><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Citation is one of the best understood branches of rent-seeking.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is Plagiarism?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/19/what-is-plagiarism.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is Plagiarism?" /><published>2020-07-19T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/19/what-is-plagiarism</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/19/what-is-plagiarism.html"><![CDATA[<p>What is a <em>doujinshi</em>, or a <em>doujin?</em> If you ask the average 14-year-old American child, they might hesitate and insist they don’t know. In their lack of eye-contact and bashful, knowing smile, you’ll see the truth: your child is checking out online porn.</p>

<p><em>Doujinshi</em> is a Japanese word for a comic created by an amateur. Japan has an incredibly active comics market, so don’t think that means <em>doujinshi</em> artists are small time. Every year, they meet up at the largest comics convention in the world, Comiket, to trade their wares. Creating <em>doujinshi</em> is one path towards building a portfolio, often by making fan based on popular ongoing series, which may be a stepping stone toward a more traditional artist jobs. It is a job, though, so they must move magazines. That means <em>doujinshi</em> artists generate a significant amount of porn. They create so much of this amateur porn, specifically hentai manga, and the fanfiction among it is so popular with the kids, that the terms <em>doujinshi</em> and hentai have essentially merged in English understanding.  The definition of <em>doujinshi</em>, essentially just “comics,” thus became “comics plus pornography.” This merger happened not because of anything the artists did, but because of how most of their audience in a certain part of the world approached their market.</p>

<p>Before I talk about plagiarism in a constructive way for the rest of this book, I must define it. Before I do that, I need to discuss the effects of definitions on our conceptual thoughts. To an American child, a <em>doujinshi</em> is porn. As I say, this is a definition with a “plus,” and we could otherwise call that a “connotation.” The longer this connotation persists, as it becomes more pronounced, it also becomes more inextricable from the concept itself. For <em>doujinshi</em>, this means the automatic reaction to “do you like <em>doujinshi?</em>” becomes more like someone’s reaction to “do you like hardcore pornography?” Again, this is entirely independent of the people who actually produce these comics in a general sense.</p>

<p>The consumers, likely enough including your child, belong to a sub-culture that defines <em>doujinshi</em> based on their sexual use of the comics. Although pornography is not necessarily a negative connotation among a more enlightened population, it is something non-essential to the thing being defined which is yet inextricable from it. When a word comes with a “plus,” it is only natural for that connotation of the word to expand in whatever direction, positive or negative, that the connotation leads it. For <em>doujinshi</em>, this means its perception will become more pornographic the longer the definition persists in this form. With this definitional drift, the semantic meaning of the word in concert with its connotation can become increasingly fluid and undefinable. As this ambiguity and inextricability become more pronounced over time, it increasingly easy to dismiss discussion of the thing in terms of its connotation. <em>Doujinshi</em> became associated with “porn” and then, over time, it became “merely porn” to the majority of people who know nothing about Comiket and Japanese comics culture.</p>

<p>These increasing inextricability and ambiguity are far from restricted merely to language differences or a norm like plagiarism. A more generally-recognizable example of this phenomenon is the definition of the term marriage. Of course, the unquestionable right same-sex couples have to the marriage institution is recognized in many countries. If we can overcome the memory hole and turn back our minds to when that was not the case, recall that marriage was defined by all sorts of dictionaries as “a union between a man and a woman.” Most popular dictionaries aim to be descriptive and follow usage, so it may not be surprising that this was the case. However, I submit to you that, just as much these dictionaries may have described usage by people with beliefs, these dictionaries were written by people with beliefs.  A definition with a “plus” connotation must survive with majority support at each previous level before a dictionary’s ink certifies it “official.” At each of those levels, the majority will believe that the word’s connotation is <em>their</em> connotation. Perhaps marriage is between a man and a woman because of sexual characteristics; perhaps it is God’s will; perhaps the government is only interested in incentivizing families (and gay couples obviously can’t adopt); perhaps they believe gay people violate the natural order.</p>

<p>None of these things would even make marriage a gender-specific term, mind you. We would still recognize a “marriage” between two concepts or two companies, for instance, because <em>marriage</em> is more a synonym for a <em>union</em> than it is anything else. And yet it was rare for a dictionary to remove the plus from these “union <em>plus</em> man and woman” definitions until marriage equality reached their own shores in legal capacities. Bigots would go down screaming after decades of activism in defense of the connotation they wanted this word to have, even if the secondary meaning never seemed so important until the “gay agenda” asked for it to be removed.</p>

<p>This is the difference between a case like <em>doujinshi</em> and same-sex marriage or, yes, plagiarism: it is unlikely any English speaker will ask for the “plus” in <em>doujinshi</em> to be removed because nobody in the English-speaking manga community is oppressed by the “plus.” The <em>mangaka</em> in Japan do not care about the English audience because they don’t pay, and it’s true enough that the English-speakers do not care because they’re getting off on it regardless. On the other hand, gay people and plagiarists have been actively suppressed by their “plus” for a long time, and their opposition to that “plus” was made unspeakable to facilitate that oppression.</p>

<p>In plainer terms, a very large subculture defined <em>marriage</em> based on their heteronormative use of the institution to disenfranchise gay people because of their “perverse” love. Similarly, a very large subculture defined <em>black</em> based on their white-nationalist use of those black people as a “perverse” underclass to raise themselves up. Transphobic people define gender based on their supposed interest in preserving outmoded ideas about how sex characteristics require people to behave, even when presented with evidence that demonstrates they’re not describing reality. For obvious reasons, it feels awkward to invoke the struggles of major oppressed communities in the defense of plagiarists, perhaps a less-existentially integral community. However, I do so for a reason. Majority oppositions arguing against a right, no matter the relative importance of that right, will bring to bear all the language and tactics innovated by majoritarians to oppress major minority groups. We will see some of these as the book goes on. For now, know that among those techniques is the definition of the minority out of existence. Gay people’s love could not be recognized as legitimate because it could not be legitimized by the state after they were defined out of the marriage institution. Black people were defined with now-unprintable words out of their own humanity. The plagiaristic artist was defined out of their own artistry. They no longer counted. To sequester them from “polite society” was worth any and all costs. We import these sorts of biases into the future by teaching them to our kids.</p>

<p>The thing that defines the contours of “polite society” when it comes to artists and how they may acceptably benefit the public is the copyright system. This book is not about the copyright system. Nonetheless, we must address some key facts about what artists believe the copyright system means before we can understand the objectionable definitions of plagiarism they concoct. Copyright is one form of what’s inaptly called “intellectual property.” Intellectual property is not a “property.” It is an incentive structure in which we create artificial scarcity on the non-rival goods created by artists on the theory they will be paid better and make more stuff. The term <em>property</em> conjures up metaphors about homes and food in ordinary people, and this deliberate conflation leads to various definitions of plagiarism which label it “theft” or otherwise “unjust taking.” You wouldn’t download a car, so this theory goes. Of course, if downloading a car for free were possible, then everyone would absolutely be doing it because cars are an investment of several thousands of dollars and the world would die in an combustion-engine-fueled climate change death spiral. We seem to be doing well enough on that front without the extra help.</p>

<p>But we should be wary of such intellectual property metaphors, as they are prone to lead us astray. We should not permit analogical reasoning to allow guilt by metaphor. What does the plagiarist “steal”? What is the nature of the “property” that anti-plagiarism norms restrict? It is not physical property. A plagiarist does not steal books; or rather, stealing books does not make one a plagiarist: This lexicon of loaded words is intended to inhibit the timid, intimidate the brash, and punish the perpetrators. In fact, the intellectual world has itself purloined the entire vocabulary of theft to characterize literary stealing, which is the ultimate in intellectual laziness. It is disconcerting that so little effort has been made to look beyond the surface features of plagiarism.</p>

<p>Most of the discourse on plagiarism does not even take into consideration that plagiarism comes in different forms. While a plagiarist can appropriate an entire work for a new purpose, a plagiarist’s copying may be quite attenuated. A novelist may insist with complete sincerity that plagiarism is the wholesale copying of someone else’s work—that is, simply changing the name on the cover—and then condemn another writer as a plagiarist because certain sentences seem plagiarized in an ultimately distinct book. A plagiarist need not even copy a single word from a work to run afoul of their local plagiarism police in academia. There, the anti-plagiarism norms prohibit copying even ideas. Yet, curiously, no act of plagiarism is actually prohibited by law in the United States. Plagiarism is not a crime. Infringing a valid copyright is the crime at issue there. Copyright can curtail marginal plagiarism from certain sources in certain circumstances, but copyright in no way defines the practice.</p>

<p>There’s a curious choice of words, though: copyright <em>does</em> define the relationship of authors to their works in a profound way. That definition, fueled by incorrect notions of “property,” takes on connotations with the same inextricability and ambiguity as our previous examples. The notion that copyrighted work is “property” and a rival good has become so inextricable from folk conceptions of copyright that many authors over the years have referred to their work as their “children.” (Children are <em>not</em> the property of their parents, and that sort of controlling language is a sign of an abusive household, but I’mma leave that alone.) The ambiguity of what people believe copyright covers has them claiming that ideas can be infringed or that lists of functional instructions like computer programs can be copyrighted. “My work is copyrighted” means whatever they want it to mean at any given time, and they want it to last forever. But, although its principles could use a restatement, copyright law is clear on the fact that copyright infringement is a crime and plagiarism is not. Copyright can limit the extent to which you can wantonly plagiarize copyrighted things, but copyright in no way defines the practice of plagiarism. Facts do not sustain the accusation that the plagiarist is a hindrance to inceptive writers who copyright their works and plagiarists who do the same.</p>

<p>So, what definition of plagiarism was imposed upon the plagiarist? There is a general theme to plagiarism definitions that follows the oppressive path sketched above. We can all agree that plagiarism involves copying from things other people created. At its core, <em>plagiarism is “unattributed copying.”</em> However—inextricably and ambiguously—plagiarism is bad and why it is bad depends on who you ask. There must be a “plus” in the definition for communities opposed to plagiarism, which often insist that certain forms of unattributed copying are acceptable. Because those forms are acceptable, they are not bad and therefore not plagiarism. Generally, very large sub-cultures defined <em>plagiarism</em> based on their desire for extra-legal property rights in their work. The motivations for those extra-legal property rights vary by community, which is why there can be so many different “plus” definitions. Each one attempts to suit the needs of its community, and perhaps that would be a laudable goal if not for the fact that anti-plagiarism policies so rarely dovetail with the stated goals of those communities.</p>

<p>As said above, defining plagiarism as “unattributed copying plus theft” is incorrect, and so is defining it as “unattributed copying plus appropriating the entire work” to inherently only include wholesale copying. Anti-plagiarists often take a different tack to the same arguments. If “literary theft” does not deprive someone of physical property, what sort of thing could be stolen? This is where we enter the encounter concepts like “credit” and definitions of plagiarism as “unattributed copying plus claiming the credit for someone else’s work.” This is obviously inaccurate because a plagiaristic piece can be as anonymous as any other, but what is “credit?” You can think of credit as a mental model where the grades we give to children at schools are reconceptualized by adults as currency. Of course, credit not being actual currency, they cannot reliably spend these rewards and even the largest store of credit can be wiped out by circumstances outside of the person’s control. Allegedly, publishing the same piece as someone else deprives the “true” author of credit for their work, but is this really so? Unless the environment builds in anti-plagiarism norms, almost certainly not.</p>

<p>For example, a student’s essay will almost always be thrown away almost immediately after having been written; what credit is being taken from anyone else? Once the grade is put in, nobody questions how it happened. On my transcript, there is one 0.0 from a class with an actively hostile teacher so awful I may have been able to get it expunged, but the reason for it is irrelevant to everyone who was not there. The only thing a low grade practically indicates is “this student is less worth hiring,” and anti-plagiarism norms do not necessarily exist outside fields that orient themselves around credit economies with academic-ish bents. So, to preserve the credit of creators whose works are plagiarized, whose credit will be entirely unaffected by that plagiarism, we are endangering students’ lives outside the context of the academic environment? Not to mention that those grades are <em>supposedly</em> given to measure student learning, and no singular metric can even measure that. The assumption that all plagiarism is “wholesale copying” helps justify this policy to teachers and anti-plagiarism creatives, but they will almost certainly punish even when that is not the case. What are they actually defending when they are defending nothing? So wide sometimes is the gulf between theory and practice.</p>

<p>No matter the specific “plus” chosen in the definition of plagiarism used by an anti-plagiarist, the connotation will be bad. It will be inextricable from their priors. If you ask them why a specific kind of plagiaristic copying is bad, they will say it is bad because it is plagiarism. If you then ask them why plagiarism is bad, they will say it’s because every form of plagiarism is bad and, moreover, equally bad. This “plus” allows those who oppose plagiarism to ignore every act which would absolutely be plagiarism if they, themselves, did not believe that act was good. This is how you get into issues with notions of authenticity and personality. Allegedly, a work of authorship is imbued with the personality of the person who composed it, and they retain an (extra-legal) interest in that piece after writing it because it represents themself. Like credit, these concepts don’t actually benefit the old author in tangible ways because, y’know, they already have their own persons, but the hypocrisy of these ideas is most apparent when you examine cases where everyone agrees it is OK to discard them.</p>

<p>Consider ghostwriting. Ghostwriting is the unattributed copying of work written by someone else; it is almost certainly the “worst” of plagiarism, wholesale copying. The named author received writing from somewhere, crossed the name out, and put their own in its place. But writers will go to their deathbeds saying that ghostwriting is not plagiarism because they made some kind of arrangement with the named author. Well, every author who enters the copyright system makes an arrangement with the government and the people that government represents. In publishing and copyrighting their works, authors absolutely do consent to their works being used in many ways implicating fair use while copyrighted, and authors absolutely do consent to the unfettered use of their work after that copyright expires. That is the arrangement. Ghostwriting with public domain resources is simply ghostwriting with ghosts, exhuming dead and forgotten things for the sake of the common welfare as well as the plagiarist’s own. There is no need to exclude this form of unattributed copying from “plagiarism” just because it makes authors uncomfortable to think of themselves as plagiarist or plagiaree here. The fact that the named author paid for the ghostwriter does not change the fact that the writing is unattributed to the ghostwriter; the fact that the named author had the idea does not change the fact that the writing is unattributed to the ghostwriter; the fact that it may have been a collaboration does not change the fact that the writing is unattributed to the ghostwriter. Ghostwriting is simply unattributed copying; that is, plagiarism.</p>

<p>We must see plagiarism for what it actually is, not what its opponents want it to be. We must define plagiarism for what plagiarists actually do, not what its opponents want to punish. It is not necessary that any one should be condemned to monotonous toil in creating. Mind, not muscle, is the motor of progress, the force which compels nature and produces wealth. In turning people into machines producing in one mode we are wasting the highest powers. Already in our society there is a favored class who need take no thought for the morrow—what they shall eat, or what they shall drink, or wherewithal they shall be clothed—with resources earned from honest work. The act common to all definitions of plagiarism is merely unattributed copying. The plagiarist, currently unfavored, is no less deserving.</p>

<p>We who see the truth, let us proclaim it, without asking who is for it or who is against it. This is not radicalism in the bad sense which so many attach to the word. This is conservatism in the true sense. By agreeing that that is the thing at issue, we can separate the negative connotations and assumptions from the idea of the practice, leaving them open to direct discussion.</p>

<p>Plagiarism is “unattributed copying,” plus nothing.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="writing," /><category term="learning," /><category term="culture," /><category term="career" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Plagiarism is Unattributed Copying]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative Commons Zero-ShareAlike 2.0 Univiral License (CC0-SA)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/11/creative-commons-zero-sharealike-2-0-univiral-license-cc0-sa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative Commons Zero-ShareAlike 2.0 Univiral License (CC0-SA)" /><published>2020-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-07-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/07/11/creative-commons-zero-sharealike-2-0-univiral-license-cc0-sa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/07/11/creative-commons-zero-sharealike-2-0-univiral-license-cc0-sa.html"><![CDATA[<p>CREATIVE COMMONS CORPORATION IS NOT A LAW FIRM AND DOES NOT PROVIDE LEGAL SERVICES. DISTRIBUTION OF THIS DOCUMENT DOES NOT CREATE AN ATTORNEY-CLIENT RELATIONSHIP. CREATIVE COMMONS PROVIDES THIS INFORMATION ON AN “AS-IS” BASIS. CREATIVE COMMONS MAKES NO WARRANTIES REGARDING THE USE OF THIS DOCUMENT OR THE INFORMATION OR WORKS PROVIDED HEREUNDER, AND DISCLAIMS LIABILITY FOR DAMAGES RESULTING FROM THE USE OF THIS DOCUMENT OR THE INFORMATION OR WORKS PROVIDED HEREUNDER.</p>

<p>By exercising the Licensed Rights (defined below), You accept and agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this CC0-ShareAlike 2.0 Univiral License (“Univiral License”). To the extent this Univiral License may be interpreted as a contract, You are granted the Licensed Rights in consideration of Your acceptance of these terms and conditions, and the Licensor grants You such rights in consideration of benefits the Licensor receives from making the Licensed Material available under these terms and conditions.</p>

<p><strong>Statement of Purpose</strong>
The laws of most jurisdictions throughout the world automatically confer exclusive Copyright and Related Rights (defined below) upon the creator and subsequent owner(s) (each and all, an “owner”) of an original work of authorship and/or a database (each, a “Work”).</p>

<p>Certain owners wish to permanently relinquish those rights to a Work for the purpose of contributing to a commons of creative, cultural and scientific works (“Commons”) that the public can reliably and without fear of later claims of infringement build upon, modify, incorporate in other works, reuse and redistribute as freely as possible in any form whatsoever and for any purposes, including without limitation commercial purposes. These owners may contribute to the Commons to promote the ideal of a free culture and the further production of creative, cultural and scientific works, or to gain reputation or greater distribution for their Work in part through the use and efforts of others. For these and/or other purposes and motivations, the Univiral License is available for use.</p>

<p>The CC0-ShareAlike (“CC0-SA”) license is a derivative of the CC0 license intended to leverage the copyleft concept of virality to actively compel the expansion of the public domain. A derivative work created by leveraging the near-public-domain-equivalent CC0-SA license must be licensed in turn under the CC0-SA license. Some might call this intellectually impure, but the folk copyright theory this license stands against is far less consistent. The Univiral License unleashes works to promote the creation of new works by everyone; folk copyright theory just restricts people and will never really promote the creation of new works.</p>

<p>The person associating CC0-SA with a Work (the “Affirmer”), to the extent that he or she is an owner of Copyright and Related Rights in the Work, voluntarily elects to apply CC0-SA to the Work and publicly distribute the Work under its terms, with knowledge of his or her Copyright and Related Rights in the Work and the meaning and intended legal effect of CC0-SA on those rights.</p>

<p><strong>1. Definitions.</strong></p>

<p>    <strong>a. Adapted Material</strong> means material subject to Copyright and Similar Rights that is derived from or based upon the Licensed Material and in which the Licensed Material is translated, altered, arranged, transformed, or otherwise modified in a manner requiring permission under the Copyright and Similar Rights held by the Licensor. For purposes of this Univiral License, where the Licensed Material is a musical work, performance, or sound recording, Adapted Material is always produced where the Licensed Material is synched in timed relation with a moving image.
    <strong>b. Adapter’s License</strong> means the license You apply to Your Copyright and Similar Rights in Your contributions to Adapted Material in accordance with the terms and conditions of this Univiral License.
    <strong>c. CC0-SA Compatible License</strong> means a license listed at creativecommons.org/compatiblelicenses, approved by Creative Commons as essentially the equivalent of this Univiral License.
    <strong>d. Copyright and Similar Rights</strong> means copyright and/or similar rights closely related to copyright including, without limitation, performance, broadcast, sound recording, and Sui Generis Database Rights, without regard to how the rights are labeled or categorized.
    <strong>e. Effective Technological Measures</strong> means those measures that, in the absence of proper authority, may not be circumvented under laws fulfilling obligations under Article 11 of the WIPO Copyright Treaty adopted on December 20, 1996, and/or similar international agreements.
    <strong>f. Exceptions and Limitations</strong> means fair use, fair dealing, and/or any other exception or limitation to Copyright and Similar Rights that applies to Your use of the Licensed Material.
    <strong>g. License Elements</strong> means the license attributes listed in the name of a Creative Commons Univiral License. The License Elements of this Univiral License are Attribution and ShareAlike.
    <strong>h. Licensed Material</strong> means the artistic or literary work, database, or other material to which the Licensor applied this Univiral License.
    <strong>i. Licensed Rights</strong> means the rights granted to You subject to the terms and conditions of this Univiral License, which are limited to all Copyright and Similar Rights that apply to Your use of the Licensed Material and that the Licensor has authority to license.
    <strong>j. Affirmer</strong> means the individual(s) or entity(ies) granting rights under this Univiral License.
    <strong>k. Share</strong> means to provide material to the public by any means or process that requires permission under the Licensed Rights, such as reproduction, public display, public performance, distribution, dissemination, communication, or importation, and to make material available to the public including in ways that members of the public may access the material from a place and at a time individually chosen by them.
    <strong>l. Sui Generis Database Rights</strong> means rights other than copyright resulting from Directive 96/9/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 11 March 1996 on the legal protection of databases, as amended and/or succeeded, as well as other essentially equivalent rights anywhere in the world.
    <strong>m. You</strong> means the individual or entity exercising the Licensed Rights under this Univiral License. Your has a corresponding meaning.</p>

<p><strong>2. Copyright and Related Rights.</strong> A Work made available under CC0-SA may be restricted by copyright and related or neighboring rights (“Copyright and Related Rights”). Copyright and Related Rights include, but are not limited to, the following:</p>

<p>    i. the right to reproduce, adapt, distribute, perform, display, communicate, and translate a Work;
    ii. moral rights retained by the original author(s) and/or performer(s);
    iii. publicity and privacy rights pertaining to a person’s image or likeness depicted in a Work;
    iv. rights protecting against unfair competition in regards to a Work, subject to the limitations in Section 6(a), below;
    v. rights protecting the extraction, dissemination, use and reuse of data in a Work;
    vi. database rights (such as those arising under Directive 96/9/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 11 March 1996 on the legal protection of databases, and under any national implementation thereof, including any amended or successor version of such directive); and
    vii. other similar, equivalent or corresponding rights throughout the world based on applicable law or treaty, and any national implementations thereof.</p>

<p><strong>3. Waiver.</strong> Under two conditions (see Section 3(a)), to the greatest extent permitted by, but not in contravention of, applicable law, Affirmer hereby overtly, fully, permanently, irrevocably and unconditionally waives, abandons, and surrenders all of Affirmer’s Copyright and Related Rights and associated claims and causes of action, whether now known or unknown (including existing as well as future claims and causes of action), in the Work (i) in all territories worldwide, (ii) for the maximum duration provided by applicable law or treaty (including future time extensions), (iii) in any current or future medium and for any number of copies, and (iv) for any purpose whatsoever, including without limitation commercial, advertising or promotional purposes (the “Waiver”). Affirmer makes the Waiver for the benefit of each member of the public at large and to the detriment of Affirmer’s heirs and successors, fully intending that such Waiver shall not be subject to revocation, rescission, cancellation, termination, or any other legal or equitable action to disrupt the quiet enjoyment of the Work by the public as contemplated by Affirmer’s express Statement of Purpose.</p>

<p>    <strong>a. License Conditions: ShareAlike.</strong></p>

<p>    In addition to the Waiver in Section 3, if You Share Adapted Material You produce, the following conditions apply.</p>

<p>        1. The Adapter’s License You apply must be a Creative Commons license with the same License Elements, this version or later, or a CC0-SA Compatible License.
        2. You may not offer or impose any additional or different terms or conditions on, or apply any Effective Technological Measures to, Adapted Material that restrict exercise of the rights granted under the Adapter’s License You apply.</p>

<p><strong>4. Endorsements.</strong>
Simultaneously while waiving the rights outlined in Section 2, Affirmer explicitly endorses the following actions You may take. The actions not enumerated to You by Section 4 are reserved to the people respectively, of which You are a member. The omission of these other actions shall not be construed to deny or disparage any possibilities conceived, or not yet conceived, by the people.</p>

<p>    a. <em>Plagiarism</em>. Plagiarism is any copying from the Work of the Affirmer to create elements of Your Adapted Material where You have omitted any attribution or acknowledgement to the Affirmer and their Work. You are encouraged to plagiarize the Work with impunity in Your Adapted Material and Affirmer’s enthusiasm for such plagiarism is beyond question.
    b. <em>Self-plagiarism</em>. Affirmer may create Adapted Material without attribution to the Affirmer in exactly the same capacity that You may create Adapted Material without attribution to the Affirmer.
    c. <em>Détournement</em>. You are encouraged to antagonistically create Adapted Material by copying the contents of the Work, repurposing it into an argument against itself.
    d. <em>Recuperation</em>. You are encouraged to antagonistically create Adapted Material by copying the contents of the Work, reframing it for the masses in a way that is non-threatening and reassuring to the powerful.
    e. <em>Permissionless distribution</em>. You are encouraged to Share the Work in any quantity via any medium or network.
    f. <em>Reverse plagiarism</em>. You are encouraged to claim an unrelated Work is the Work and attribute it to Affirmer.
    g. <em>Parody</em>. You are encouraged to appropriate the Work in order to make any satirical or ironic point with Your Adapted Material.
    h. <em>Theft</em>. You are encouraged to steal any and all tangible copies of the Work.
    i. <em>Prestidigitation</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work in magical tricks and any displays of legerdemain extant, extinct, or yet to be invented.
    j. <em>Scoring</em>. You are encouraged to create a musical score to accompany this book as Adapted Material.
    l. <em>Fun</em>. You are encouraged to have fun in any way You can during the creation of Your Adapted Material.
    k. <em>Profit</em>. You are encouraged to profit from Your Adapted Material if You so choose.
    m. <em>Face-to-face instruction</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work during face-to-face classroom sessions.
    n. <em>Virtual instruction</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work during remote classroom sessions via any network.
    o. <em>Destruction</em>. You are encouraged to destroy any and all copies of the Work with whatever means You prefer.
    p. <em>Translating</em>. You are encouraged to translate the Work into any natural or constructed language extant, extinct, or yet to be invented.
    q. <em>Obscuring</em>. You are encouraged to deface any and all copies of the Work such that they are no longer legible.
    r. <em>Derivative work</em>. In creating Your Adapted Material, You are encouraged to make any and all sorts of derivative works.
    s. <em>Nominative use</em>. You are encouraged to use the title of the Work in Your own Work.
    t. <em>Intertextuality</em>. You are encouraged to create any new Work which requires encountering the Work before fully comprehending the new Work.
    u. <em>Pastiche</em>. You are encouraged to copy the Work’s style to evoke its tangible elements rather than copy them directly.
    v. <em>Allusion</em>. If You would prefer to not copy the Work’s elements at all, You are encouraged to surreptitiously refer to the Work and these elements in a manner only understandable to those who have previously encountered the Work.
    w. <em>De minimis</em>. In addition to copying as much as possible from the Work, You are encouraged to copy as little as possible.
    x. <em>Eroticism</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work for any lewd purpose.
    y. <em>Pierre Menard</em>. You are encouraged to attribute the Work to Pierre Menard in particular.
    z. <em>Hypertext</em>. You are encouraged to use any hypertext techniques to connect the Work with any other Work(s), not limited to jump links.
    α. <em>Anthologize</em>. You are encouraged to collect the Work or any portion of the Work into any anthology.
    β. <em>Stripped</em>. In the event that the Work is intended to be sold with a cover and the Work has been stripped of that cover for the purpose of pulping or recycling, know that it was reported as “unsold and destroyed” to the publisher and is stolen property. Cool.
    γ. <em>Fictionalization</em>. You are encouraged to depict the contents of the Work in fictional scenarios within Your Adapted Material, especially if the Work is non-fiction.
    δ. <em>Rebinding</em>. You are encouraged to rebind or otherwise repackage the Work in whatever manner You choose.
    ε. <em>Serialization</em>. The Work may be serialized in whole or in part.
    ζ. <em>Multimedia adaptation</em>. You are encouraged to create Adapted Material in any medium extant, extinct, or yet to be invented.
    ι. <em>Tweet</em>. You are encouraged to tweet the contents of this Work in whole or in part on Twitter, including thoughts inspired by the Work.
    κ. <em>Toot</em>. You are encouraged to toot the contents of this Work in whole or in part on Mastodon, including thoughts inspired by the Work.
    λ. <em>Handmake</em>. You are encouraged to recreate the Work by hand using whatever materials or techniques You wish.
    μ. <em>Sing</em>. You are encouraged to sing the contents of the Work to any tune You wish.
    ν. <em>Queering</em>. You are encouraged to challenge any perceived heteronormativity, cisnormativity, or other manifestation of the domination or limitation of an oppressed group based on their identity, especially those constrained by unrepresentative binary social constructs, as depicted in the Work; You are encouraged to use an analysis that is intentionally anti-discriminatory on the basis of sexuality, gender, or any other form of identity.
    ξ. <em>Pooh bear</em>. You are encouraged to create Adapted Material which incorporates Christopher Robin’s teddy bear, Pooh.
    ο. <em>Ozma</em>. You are encouraged to tithe the Work to Ozma, Child Queen and Rightful Ruler of the Land of Oz.
    π. <em>Food</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work for food or bake it into any sort of foodstuff.
    ρ. <em>Rotation</em>. You are encouraged to reproduce the work in any combination of alternative angular orientations.
    σ. <em>Simplification</em>. You are encouraged to simply the contents of this book to any degree and portray it as a Work You created because You did create a new Work.
    τ. <em>Tautology</em>. If Your use is listed here or if Your use is not listed here, Your use is encouraged.
    υ. <em>Unpopulate</em>. You are encouraged to adapt the Work without reference to any persons mentioned within.
    φ. <em>Fortune telling</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work to determine the future whether or not Your method is in conjunction with any other method of clairvoyance extant, extinct, or yet to be discovered.
    χ. <em>Keychains</em>. You are encouraged to merchandise the Work in any way You choose, including the manufacture of Keychains to aid in opening gates to new worlds.
    ψ. <em>Psychics</em>. You are encouraged to use the Work in displays of Extra Sensory Perception and Psychic abilities.
    ω. <em>Fair Use/Dealing</em>. You are encouraged to rely on an exception to copyright that resembles Fair Use to justify the creation of Your Adapted Material if You are cringe and blue-pilled.</p>

<p><strong>5. Univiral License Fallback.</strong> Should any part of the Waiver for any reason be judged legally invalid or ineffective under applicable law, then the Waiver shall be preserved to the maximum extent permitted taking into account Affirmer’s express Statement of Purpose. In addition, to the extent the Waiver is so judged Affirmer hereby grants to each affected person a royalty-free, non transferable, non sublicensable, non exclusive, irrevocable and unconditional license to exercise Affirmer’s Copyright and Related Rights in the Work (i) in all territories worldwide, (ii) for the maximum duration provided by applicable law or treaty (including future time extensions), (iii) in any current or future medium and for any number of copies, and (iv) for any purpose whatsoever, including without limitation commercial, advertising or promotional purposes (the “License”), subject to the conditions listed in Section 3(a). The License shall be deemed effective as of the date CC0-SA was applied by Affirmer to the Work. Should any part of the License for any reason be judged legally invalid or ineffective under applicable law, such partial invalidity or ineffectiveness shall not invalidate the remainder of the License, and in such case Affirmer hereby affirms that he or she will not (i) exercise any of his or her remaining Copyright and Related Rights in the Work or (ii) assert any associated claims and causes of action with respect to the Work, in either case contrary to Affirmer’s express Statement of Purpose. If it is determined that this license has been infringed, the only acceptable remedy is the licensing of the Adapted Material under CC0-SA.</p>

<p><strong>6. Limitations and Disclaimers.</strong></p>

<p>    a. No trademark or patent rights held by Affirmer are waived, abandoned, surrendered, licensed or otherwise affected by this document.
    b. Affirmer offers the Work as-is and makes no representations or warranties of any kind concerning the Work, express, implied, statutory or otherwise, including without limitation warranties of title, merchantability, fitness for a particular purpose, non infringement, or the absence of latent or other defects, accuracy, or the present or absence of errors, whether or not discoverable, all to the greatest extent permissible under applicable law.
    c. Affirmer disclaims responsibility for clearing rights of other persons that may apply to the Work or any use thereof, including without limitation any person’s Copyright and Related Rights in the Work. Further, Affirmer disclaims responsibility for obtaining any necessary consents, permissions or other rights required for any use of the Work.
    d. Affirmer understands and acknowledges that Creative Commons is not a party to this document and has no duty or obligation with respect to this CC0-SA or use of the Work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="copyright," /><category term="writing," /><category term="licenses," /><category term="copyleft" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Make the public domain go viral.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Speed Up Netflix Without Installing Anything</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/30/how-to-speed-up-netflix-without-installing-anything.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Speed Up Netflix Without Installing Anything" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/06/30/how-to-speed-up-netflix-without-installing-anything</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/06/30/how-to-speed-up-netflix-without-installing-anything.html"><![CDATA[<div class="language-js highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="nb">document</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">querySelector</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">video</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">playbackRate</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mf">0.5</span><span class="p">;</span>

<span class="nb">document</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">querySelector</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">video</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">playbackRate</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mf">1.5</span><span class="p">;</span>

<span class="nb">document</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">querySelector</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">video</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">playbackRate</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mf">2.0</span><span class="p">;</span>

<span class="nb">document</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">querySelector</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="s1">video</span><span class="dl">'</span><span class="p">).</span><span class="nx">playbackRate</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="mf">3.0</span><span class="p">;</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>I don’t want to install anything just to speed up Netflix. If you do, <a href="https://thedroidguy.com/change-netflix-playback-speed-1119495">there are options</a>. For my part, whenever I move to a new computer, I look up this incantation. I’m posting it myself to speed that up next time.</p>

<p>Open your browser’s inspection tool to get to the JavaScript console, then enter this line of code with a number corresponding to the speed. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.0</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2</code> is 2x speed. It takes any non-negative number, including numbers between <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">0</code> and <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1</code> to slow down the video. (<code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">0</code> pauses playback.) It also works for any HTML5 video, not just Netflix. The <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">'video'</code> string is the default name and extremely common, although the website <em>can</em> change it to something else.</p>

<p>The real solution to this problem is Netflix exposing the HTML5 speed controls through their interface, but they are ghouls who refuse to do that. Likewise, there are creeps in Hollywood who insist they have some fictional right to make you watch TV at 1x speed against your will, and they lobby Netflix to prevent this functionality that already exists. They’re making choices for you, and they are choosing to waste your life away. Be the lowest-tier cyberpunk you can be and take your time back from these monsters. At least, when you want to.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="tips," /><category term="productivity," /><category term="javascript," /><category term="tutorial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[document.querySelector('video').playbackRate = 2;]]></summary></entry></feed>